<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Victor Nagahama</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Victor Nagahama</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification of soybean seeds based on images via Transfer Learning</title>
      <link>/posts/soybean-image-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/soybean-image-classification/</guid>
      <description>In July of 2020 I&amp;rsquo;ve joined the AI Residency program from HUB of Artificial Intelligence, in this program the AI residents perform proof of concepts (POC) for companies meanwhile have classes from researchers of Advanced Institute for Artificial Intelligence.
One of the challenges as an AI resident was to classify soybeans based on images in order to improve the selection of seeds. Soybean seeds are classified according to their qualities and it&amp;rsquo;s an important information to industry and soybean farmers because of the control quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Victor Hugo Nagahama Bachelor in statistics, data scientist and aspiring musician. Nowadays I&amp;rsquo;m in residency program of HUB of Artificial Intelligence of SENAI.
I&amp;rsquo;m passionate with music in special Brazillian music. I try to live in between the worlds of data analysis, music and literature. By the way, why not hear my indie band Colombus St.?
The blog In this blog I have the opportunity to venture into data science and AI, some post are about real applications, studies, tips or even problems that you may not think to use data analysis in the first time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitae (CV)</title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description>You can download my CV in this link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the data in data science problems</title>
      <link>/posts/data-understanding-in-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/data-understanding-in-data-science/</guid>
      <description>In the last weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve started a selection process in a data science course sponsored by Codenation. To join in this program it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to be approved on the selection challenge, which was to predict the math scores of students of ENEM 2016.
ENEM is a college entrance exam applied in Brazil, students can get a position in public universities or a financial support. ENEM is the second biggest exam in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding the Dream Team in FIFA 20 using Linear Programming</title>
      <link>/posts/dream-team-fifa20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/dream-team-fifa20/</guid>
      <description>In my childhood me and my friends used to guess what would be the soccer Dream Team of the season. We hadn&amp;rsquo;t any metrics to compare our choices, so the results were doubtful.
Recently, I found this dataset about FIFA on Kaggle. The data contains the scores of 18.279 players in all of the 27 soccer positions (goalkeeper, centre forward, etc).
Motivated by my childhood I used this data and Linear Programming (LP) to find the set of players which sum maximizes the overall team score, in other words, the Dream Team.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>